Downloaded @ subs4free.club
When we take it upon ourselves
to act against
our best interests...
...and the best interests
of our community,
we have to understand that
there are consequences
for those actions.
And we must respect
the hierarchy of power
as it is handed down
to us from God.
I did not ask for
this responsibility.
I did rise to power
under my own volition,
but the drive to do so
was placed inside of me
by a higher power.
Jimmy...
It's God's will
that I stand here today...
to take a hard look
at your lives, people.
You believe that anything
happens without the will of God.
If it were God's will
that He wanted one of you
- to be in charge...
- Hey, Briggs.
...do you not think He
would have given you the drive?
Keep a sharp eye out
for the brother.
Boss thinks he might
try something.
He did not.
God blessed me with the means
and the mental fortitude
to grow my interests
in this community.
Not only was I able to open up
Clark's Mercantile and Trade,
but I was able to
lure in the railroad.
Now I know that many of you do
not agree with my methods.
Let me assure you
Mister McCallister
here's had every opportunity
to do right by this community,
but he's flat out refused.
Jimmy...
you go on home, now.
Don't stay here and watch this.
You hear me, son?
You go on home!
Go!
"James," is it?
Do you understand what's
happening here today?
Well, your father is teaching
you a valuable lesson.
Go home!
Go!
Know your place.
He stole from me.
Yes, he did. Yes, he did!
He stole from
all these good people.
That makes him a sinner.
You know where in
the world sinners go?
I can tell you.
Sure as hell ain't Wyoming.
Let him hang.
Shoot the wagon driver.
Pa!
Get Briggs!
Please help me!
Dad, you okay?
Briggs... help me...
Get the doc.
You owe me more.
- You okay?
- Yeah.
Bobby...
Oh, God, no.
Paid in full.
You killed my brother,
you son of a...!
Have to get these hung early
so they have a chance to dry
before the wind gets up.
Are you gonna help me
or just keep watching?
I like watching you.
Yeah? You like
watching me hang laundry?
I like watching you
do most things.
Most things I do, I do for you.
That's true.
Suppose that might be
why you like watching me.
I reckon I'd enjoy watching
you do other things.
Not just things for me.
Like when I do things
for our daughter?
Yes. You're a good mother.
Anyone can see that.
Thank you.
Now, I need you to be
a good father today
and walk our daughter to school.
Oh, no. She's old enough
to walk herself.
She needs you.
I need you.
And I can't walk her today
since the wind is probably
gonna get up
and I need to finish
hanging this laundry.
I have to open the store.
Then the two of you best
get going so you're not late.
Brooke!
You need to hurry.
Your father's walking you
to school today.
Why can't you walk me?
Brooke.
Yes, sir?
Listen to your mother.
Thank you. Brooke,
I have too many chores
to get done this morning.
So no arguing.
Grab your school books
and scoot before
you're both late.
I think you and your father
could use a little
walk together anyway.
Go on.
- We should have taken the horse.
- No.
There wasn't time to
saddle the horse
and walk you to school
and be back at the store
on time to open.
- Wouldn't we be faster on the horse?
- Undoubtedly.
Then wouldn't the time
we save by being faster
have made up for the time
it would have taken
to saddle the horse?
No.
"No classes today as
Miss Valerie has taken ill."
What do you think
she's ill with?
Pox?
It's probably pox.
You need to walk home now.
I have to open the store.
Mama says I'm not
allowed to walk home alone.
That's nonsense.
You say I should
listen to Mother.
This is different.
Mama wouldn't like it if
you made me walk home alone.
Sit there and finish
your studies.
I finished my studies.
The teacher needs
to assign new ones.
Then sit there and read a book.
Good morning, Mister Jeffries.
Good morning, Mister Briggs.
- How's your day?
- Very well.
How can I help you?
Well, I'll tell you,
Mister Briggs.
My mother done got it
in her head yesterday
that she wanted to bake a cake
for the church potluck
this weekend.
And now last year,
she made a pie,
but the apples she used grew on
Mister Johnson's apple tree.
You know, the one out back
by the outhouse?
And wouldn't you know it,
them apples tasted plum-like shit
and made anybody who eat
them sick to they gut.
I tell ya', I think the shit
from that outhouse
has soaked down to the root
and changed the way
a basic apple can taste.
But Mister Johnson says
that's a bunch of hooey,
and because of that, he won't
let Mama have no more apples
for her apple pie, which,
as far as I'm concerned,
is fine by me and Mama
because as I mentioned before,
the apples taste
like shit anyhow.
Well, that left
a dilemma for Mama.
She's not going to bake pie
for this week's potluck.
What could she possibly make?
A cake.
Exactly.
Mama's gonna bake a cake.
Bring it to the church potluck
after church on Sunday.
Was there something
that you needed
from the store, Mister Jeffries?
There I go, blundering
on around about Mama.
I done forgot you don't
know why I'm here.
Mama needs some flour.
The sack she has
is full of weevils
and she don't think she can
sift them all out this time.
How many pounds?
Just a 20-pound bag'll do.
I didn't, uh,
I didn't see you there.
I wasn't really gonna steal 'em.
It's just a game
I play with your daddy.
Twenty pounds of flour.
That'll be one dollar
and a nickel.
Yeah, could you apply it
to my mother's account?
- Of course.
- Thank you, Mister Briggs.
Hope to see you
at the luncheon on Sunday.
Madam.
Have you finished
reading your book?
He tried to steal
some jelly beans.
- What?
- That man.
Mr. Jeffries?
I caught him taking
some jelly beans
and he put them back.
He put them back?
He did.
I'll discuss this with him
next time he's in my store.
You want one?
No.
Then what do you want?
His hands were dirty.
Pardon me, ma'am.
I didn't mean to frighten you.
We weren't sure if
anyone was home.
Someone is home.
Me. How can I help you?
Yes, ma'am.
First, me apologize for the
rudeness of my introduction.
My name is James McCallister,
and me and my companions
have been on the road
for several days now.
We're plum tired and we're
more than a little lost.
"Companions?"
Uh, yes, ma'am.
That's Boots there,
out by the road.
He didn't want to ride up to
the house and frighten folks.
He's being polite.
And behind you,
well, that's Big Mike.
Thousand pardons, Miss.
I was just around back
checking to see if
there's anybody in your garden.
Was there?
Nope.
You gentlemen should
have just knocked.
Well, we did knock, ma'am.
Hm, that's true.
Saw Big Mike step up to
that door and give it a rap.
Most definitely witnessed
that with mine own.
Must not have knocked too loud.
I certainly didn't
hear it in the house.
Nevertheless...
Well, if you gentlemen will
just allow me a moment
to put the laundry down,
I will happily point you
in the direction of town.
It's about a half hour's
walk up the road.
And they've got hotels
and saloons,
and a hot bath house
with a brand-new shower.
Well, that would be
an act of kindness, ma'am.
We'd be much obliged.
My husband will be along
any minute,
so he might even be able to
show you the way himself.
Your husband?
Yes, sir. My husband.
He should be along any moment.
Would your husband
happen to have been
that feller we saw walking
down the road earlier?
Walking with a little girl?
Yes, he was walking
our daughter to school.
Oh, ain't that somethin'?
A grown man walking
a little girl to school.
We certainly live in a new age.
- Sure does seem like it.
- Sure does.
You said town's about a half
an hour walk up the road?
That's right.
Hm. Well...
your man sure been
gone a long time
if he was just walking your
daughter to school and back.
Sure hope nothin' happened
to hold him up.
Go help him.
You all right?
The bitch kicked me
in the balls.
You got your ass whooped by an
unarmed woman doing her laundry.
- Yeah.
- You sure you have balls?
Open up, Missy.
I'm coming in
one way or another.
Might as well not
piss us off in the meantime.
Madam...
I think you got the wrong idea
about me and the fellas.
Ain't no sense
runnin' off and hidin'.
We don't want to hurt nobody.
We need to quit peckerin' around
and get back on the trail.
That marshal can't
be too far behind.
A day, day and a half at most.
We need to keep moving
unless you fools
want to end up back in jail.
Eustice, shut your damn mouth.
Now I know you're scared
and you're hiding.
If you'll just
poke your head out,
you'll see we don't
got any guns.
We just want to talk.
Go on. Go get her.
Bring her back.
- You gon' live?
- Yeah.
Bring her over! Quickly now!
Her arm's all busted up.
That's fine. That's fine.
I feel like we got off to a bad start.
And I'm going to
put that on you.
Now, when we first met,
I introduced myself, did I not?
I said my name, loud and clear.
You did not do me
the same honor. Did ya'?
I said, did ya'?
You'll get no honor from me.
Tell me this then, huh?
Is this your husband? Hm?
Is he the man we saw walking
down the street this morning?
Is your husband
the Colton Briggs?
Heard of my husband, have you?
Oh, I've certainly
heard of your husband.
We're like family, me and him.
Good.
That saves me the trouble
of explaining it to you.
You boys are in a world...
of hurt.
Who the shit is Colton Briggs?
Are you serious?
Colton Briggs?
This is Colton Briggs' place?
Eustice, quiet.
That's right.
And I'm his wife.
And you hit me...
in the face with your gun.
Broke my arm.
Shot his horse.
You boys have woke up the devil.
God damn it, Jimmy.
You bringing hell down on us!
I absolutely
know your husband, hm.
We go way back.
In fact, I owe him a debt.
That'll do.
It's time to head home.
Mama didn't come
to get me from school.
You weren't at school.
You were here.
Yes, but wouldn't she
come here to find me
if I wasn't at school?
Hey, Marshal!
You better come on out here.
Who are those men?
What do we got here? The family?
Maybe it looks like
the father and the daughter
from that picture
on the mantle in there.
They must've been away
when those fellas came through.
Thank God they're okay.
A little bit of luck, finally.
Lucky, indeed.
Tell the others to come outside.
We shouldn't be making
ourselves comfortable
in these folks' home.
Hey, you guys...
family's here.
- They're still alive?
- Yup.
Oh, shit.
This you folks home?
I want to apologize for my men.
We, uh, we didn't realize that
no one was home and...
My wife was home.
Yes, sir. l... uh...
I apologize again.
My name is US Marshall
Franklin Jarrett.
I know who you are.
Where's Ruth?
I'm afraid you have me
at a loss, sir.
Do I know you?
Briggs?
Well holy shit, man.
I, uh...
I apologize, little lady.
That language is, uh,
not appropriate.
You have a family?
Well, that is a good thing.
A man needs a family.
It, uh, grounds him.
Evens him out.
That is... this is good.
Marshal...
I'm sorry, Briggs, but...
we need to talk.
Somewhere private, preferably.
Why don't you boys go
help him dig that hole?
Says he don't want our help.
Says we should've been
better at our jobs.
He ain't wrong.
- Go get them horses ready.
- Hmm.
Little lady...
I had Smiley heat up
some of that condensed milk
and put a little
brown sugar in it.
It's good. Make you feel better.
I never knew your mama.
But I know she was a good woman.
But I did know your daddy.
Years and years ago.
You meet a lot of people
in this business,
and the faces, a lot of times,
just disappear over the years.
But not your daddy.
No, sir. Not him.
Your daddy was about
the meanest son of a bitch
I ever met.
Pardon my language, but...
I never met anybody like him.
Just the way he would
look at you, just...
like he was looking through you.
Like you were nothing.
And I don't say this lightly,
but y... your daddy
was a violent man.
I've seen him shoot
three cowboys one time.
Now it was a fair fight, but...
I don't think his blood
raised an ounce.
I can't say he was a criminal.
I don't know that,
but I can say that he...
was not what I would
call a "good man."
Not back then.
Why are you telling me this?
Hm.
I guess I just want you
to understand...
how good a woman your mama was.
She took the coldest killer
that I've ever met,
and she turned him
into a family man.
Minding a store.
Raising a little lady.
That was a good thing
your mama done.
My father used to kill people?
Yeah.
But that was years ago.
I haven't even seen
my father hold a gun.
And that's because
he's a good man now.
Because of what your mama done.
You carry a gun.
Are you a good man?
I try to be.
My mama's dead now.
Is my father still a good man?
Would you like for me
to say a few words?
You said plenty of words.
None of them helped.
There's something
you should know.
Um, them fellas left
a mess in your barn.
Not something your
little girl should see.
You'll wanna clean that up
before you let her go in there.
I reckon we'll be
hitting the trail.
I figured we're only
a few hours behind 'em.
And I think I've got a pretty
good idea where they're going.
Tell me the names of
the men who did this.
Tell me where they're going.
No, sir.
I don't think I can do that.
I reckon it's been
a few years since the world
has seen the old Colton Briggs
and I think the world
is probably pretty happy
leaving that just
right where it is.
Tell me the names of the men
responsible for
the death of my wife.
Briggs, listen to yourself.
You see that
little girl over there?
She just lost her mama.
She needs her father now.
Whatever changes happened to
you that that woman gave you,
don't let 'em die with her.
That little girl needs the man
that she knows and loves.
You know, ever since
we were granted statehood,
this here land is now
part of a new country.
We got laws. We got due process.
Folks just don't go around
killin' other folks.
That ain't the world anymore.
Keep right by your daughter.
Keep right by God.
I will find those
murderous sons of bitches.
I will catch 'em.
We will take them to trial,
and they will hang.
I promise that to you.
Take care of your daughter.
As long as that
little girl is alive,
there's no room for
vengeance in your life.
What do we do now?
Go to bed.
I need you.
"As long as she's alive."
Mama wouldn't like you
pointing that gun at me.
Get dressed.
Those are pants.
No dresses.
We leave in 15 minutes.
This is Mama's horse.
Yeah. They killed mine.
We'll have to travel light.
She can't run with both of us.
If we're gonna catch up
with those men,
we're gonna need another horse.
Yeah. We'll find one
along the way.
This is a good time
for us to do this.
My teacher at school is sick.
If it's pox, she could
be sick for days.
She could die.
They'll get a new teacher.
I forgot my school books.
- I think they burned up in the fire.
- We'll get new books.
- What about my clothes?
- We'll get new clothes.
Why did we burn the old ones?
Because we're not going back!
We're not going back.
As soon as I finish
what I have to do,
we'll find a new place and...
we'll replace
everything you lost.
Except Mama.
Give me the belt.
You gonna whoop me?
Take that.
Over there by that tree,
off the path.
You can sleep for 30 minutes,
not longer.
Then we'll eat,
and we'll get back on trail.
We'll do that every four hours
until we catch 'em.
Aren't those men
getting further away?
They're only men.
They need sleep as well.
They'll wait for us.
But if we keep going,
we can be there sooner,
- before anything...
- Won't do us no good if we get there dead tired.
Or if our horse
dies from exhaustion.
It's not enough
that we find these men.
We need to be ready to kill 'em.
Because they'll be
meaning to kill us.
Did that seem strange to you?
That little girl last night?
How do you mean?
Her mama had just been killed.
She was sittin' there right
next to the body.
Not a tear on her face.
Hell, I never even
met the woman.
I cried more about it
than her own daughter.
Well, she's probably just
shocked from the news.
I mean, her mama was just killed.
She ain't never coming back.
Gotta be hard for any
youngster to understand.
I suppose so.
Holy shit!
Come on. Come on. Come on.
Holy shit, son.
How'd you do that?
My leg is busted.
That one's a shooter, shit.
It's that marshal.
You didn't shoot the marshal?
God damn it!
That asshole started the ambush
before we're in position!
What do we do?
Do you see Briggs?
Shit, boss, I don't know
what he looks like.
Oh, you'll know
when you see him.
I promise you that.
Get down, Smiley!
Oh!
Dumbass.
Let's see how far
them bastards get now.
Boss is pulling out.
Next reload,
let's get up that hill.
I'm out of here!
God help us.
Is it time to leave?
I heard gunshots coming
from across the canyon.
- When?
- Ten minutes ago.
Why didn't you wake me?
No reason to hurry.
Gunshots might have a way of
speeding some folks up, but...
they have a nasty habit of
slowing other folks down.
We'll find out what
happened soon enough.
Either way.
I can't believe you.
You want to tell me what
the hell just happened? Huh?
What the hell, boss?
Those guys up front, they were
about to go behind the hill.
I wouldn't have
seen 'em if I waited.
You were supposed to shoot
the Marshal first. Huh?
Instead, genius here decides to
shoot the first guy he sees,
chasing everybody, including
the marshal, into cover.
You know...
I go to enormous pains
to invite Colton Briggs
to come find me.
You go ahead and leave a perfectly
healthy lawman between us.
It's like you're trying
to work against me.
Is that what's
happening here? Huh?
You're working against me?
Nah, boss.
I'm with you.
I just messed up. That's all.
I certainly hope so.
Because if that
lawman stops Briggs
before he can get to me...
there will be hell to pay.
Mm.
It don't matter for nothing.
You got somethin' to say,
old man?
If Colton Briggs
decides he's coming,
you might as well set
an extra plate at the table
because Colton Briggs is coming.
What's going on?
There's a rider coming.
One of the men who killed Mama?
Maybe one of the men
from the posse?
Either way, we need his horse.
- Are you gonna kill him?
- I'm gonna take his horse.
Chances are, he won't
like me doing that.
I don't think Mama would
like you killin' no lawman.
I don't know if he is a lawman.
Chances are he won't stop
and give me time to ask.
Can't you think of
another way to stop him?
He'll be coming from
that direction.
You stand there
and get him to stop.
How?
Cry. Make him
feel sorry for you.
I don't know how.
What did you just say?
I don't know how to cry.
Now, you listen to me.
People in this world
expect you to act like they do.
They expect you to laugh
at their jokes,
and sigh at their babies,
and cry at their funerals.
And if you can't learn
to do those things,
they won't accept you.
They'll push you out.
Now, do you wanna
make it in this world?
Answer me! Do you wanna fit in?
Then you're going to have
figure out how to act like them.
You remember last summer when
the parson's daughter died?
You remember how his wife cried?
Wahh wahh!
A little louder. Wahh wahh!
My baby! My baby!
Wahh wahh! My baby! My baby!
That'll have to do. Keep it up.
Wahh wahh! Wahh wahh!
Wahh wahh!
You okay, little girl?
Wahh! My baby! My baby! Wahh!
Baby? What baby?
What? What are you getting at?
Wahh!
You're gettin' off that horse.
You should have gone with Mark.
He looked pretty bad.
And what? Leave you two
here without protection?
I ain't helpless.
Don't shoot. Don't shoot.
It's me.
Shit, Mark.
You scared the hell out of us.
What the hell are you
doing back here?
Where's your horse?
Ask them.
What the hell?!
I'm sorry, guys.
Now, Briggs,
I know you're upset.
Hell, I don't blame you.
But whatever
you think you're doing,
you need to let these boys go.
Fetch that Rossi
and bring it here.
My father wants your shotgun.
Do what she says, Greg.
I will blow this little girl's
brains all over this valley.
Do you hear me?
I said I will blow her brains
all over this valley.
I'll pull the trigger right now!
He cries pretty good.
I'm gonna try and do it
like him next time.
Both of you put your hands
behind your back.
Is this enough wood?
That wood's too green.
It needs to burn hotter.
See the tip of that?
Should burn so hot it glows red.
Fetch dry wood.
It burns hotter.
It burns faster.
Listen to me, Briggs.
Just listen to me.
Up till now, you haven't
committed any crimes
that you can't walk away from.
I understand that you're
under a lot of pressure,
pain of losing your wife.
I can't imagine it.
Any man might have done
the same thing.
Made some of the same
decisions that you've made.
But you are about to
cross a line
that you can't get back from.
Assaulting a US Marshal,
murdering a US Marshal,
that is trouble that you have
not encountered before.
Are you sure about that?
What about your daughter,
Briggs?
You're making her an accessory.
These men here need
medical attention
and you are preventing
them from getting it.
No. You are.
By not telling me
what I want to know.
I'm a federal marshal.
You're asking me to
participate in murder.
You're protecting a killer.
From another killer.
Correct.
Is this dry enough?
Good. Put it on the fire.
We'll be ready to start soon.
If anything happens to my men,
I swear to God,
I will hunt you down
and I will kill you myself.
Like you hunted down the
man who killed my wife?
The man who killed your men?
The man responsible for
everything happening right now?
I'll take my chances.
Rip his shirt.
Don't you touch me!
Give him the stick
like I showed you.
- Please... stop...
- James McCallister!
Name's James McCallister.
He rides with three men,
Michael Orleans and Boots Miller
and Eustice Bedford.
They're all hardened criminals.
Word is, he promised them
a share of a lockbox
he's got stashed somewhere
if they'd bust him out of
the prison in Powell County.
And they're headed to Colorado.
Somebody told me he's got a
little Mexican girl down there
in a town he likes
called Santa Rosa.
The trail I was on meant that
he was headed that way.
And that's all I know
about it. I swear it.
Hold him.
- No, no.
- Oh, you son of a bitch!
I will kill you, you son of a bitch!
Bring me the iron.
Pinch the flesh on each side of
the wound and push it together.
We have to burn it with the iron
or he'll bleed out soon.
Smells like Mama's rabbit chops.
Mm, that's the whiskey.
Makes me hungry.
Mm-hmm.
The bullet was poisoning him.
He's got a chance now.
But these men are not
walking out of this canyon.
If get to Santa Rosa...
and there's
no James McCallister,
no Mexican girl,
no gang of four,
I will come back here
and I will kill these two men
before you can return with help.
And then, I will wait for you.
And no matter how many men
you bring back with you,
I will kill you first.
I will kill you...
before you even see me.
Do you understand?
We're taking your guns
and your horse.
You gotta leave me
a horse, Briggs!
- You can't take my horse!
- Take your mother's horse.
- This one suits me fine.
- Damn it, don't question me.
You've got more experience
with your mother's horse.
She knows you. Fewer surprises.
Now get up.
I'll leave your horse
tied up in Santa Rosa.
I'm no horse thief.
Justice is gonna
find you, Briggs.
- H'yah!
- You hear me? God damn you.
Justice will catch you!
There.
Just like I told you boys.
Let's crack her open
and see what we got.
Oh, lordy.
Whoo-hoo!
"El Banco Londres Y Mexico"?
What the hell?
Now settle down.
What the hell, boss?
Where's the money, boss?
Now, if I was crossing you,
I would have killed you already.
But I didn't.
Nothing but a dirty rat...
You ain't too bright now,
is you?
But that's okay.
That's why you got me.
I got brains.
And my brains know that since
we busted out of jail,
we're gonna have to
lay low for a while.
At least a year or so.
Any of you boys got any idea
what kind of money
they spend down in Mexico? Hm?
Right there,
that's enough dinero
for each of us
to live like kings
for as long as we need.
Each of you get an equal share,
hm, as long as
you stick with me.
Or, we can split it up here
and part ways as friends.
But I will tell you this.
That money...
well, ain't worth a nickel
this side of the border.
Not unless you know
where to spend it.
And boys...
I do.
What about this Briggs fella?
Yeah, we're gonna have to
figure that out
and figure it out fast.
It's all part of the plan.
Should we wait for him
and set a ambush
like we did for the marshal?
We don't know how far
behind us Briggs might be.
We could be sittin'
in the bush for days.
And two, Briggs
ain't the type of man
to walk into
an ambush unprepared.
Then how do we hunt him down?
I thought I made myself clear.
We ain't huntin' nobody.
Briggs is huntin' us.
What do we need that for?
It's good firewood.
That was on someone's grave.
So?
It belongs to someone.
Nothing belongs to the dead...
because the dead
don't need anything.
Only the living
need to possess things.
The living need food,
water, shelter,
clothes, family,
money, and land.
But the dead, the dead've
already been tended to.
Once they're put in the ground,
they have all they need.
They're not selfish.
I like the dead.
I don't like this.
There's a sheriff.
Well, the sheriff's in Denver.
Two days away.
We cut the telegraph lines
coming into town,
which means it'll be
upwards of four days
before any sheriff can get
the news that we're here
and show up to do
anything about it.
That office is where
they keep the bad folks
until the lawman
can come pick 'em up.
Still...
feelin' mighty exposed
ridin' into town like this.
You gonna question
my every call?
Now, I need you boys
to set a guard
at the edge of town, all right?
Anyone rides in,
you let me know.
And rotate every couple hours.
Y'all look like dog shit.
I need you rested for
when Briggs gets here
or you're of no use to me.
Understand?
And ladies,
I assume you're well rested.
I am in need of your services.
You heard him.
Who wants first watch?
Well, I'll take first watch.
But you better come
and relieve me in four hours.
You want to
give me a hand with this?
That marshal said
you used to kill people.
That marshal should
guard his words
when speaking to children.
Is it true?
Yes.
He said you gave it up.
He said you gave it up for Mama.
Is that true?
He said Mama changed you.
My entire life...
even as a boy, I knew.
I knew I was different.
My mother always said
I didn't cry as a baby.
I didn't laugh.
When my mother died,
I was very young,
but I didn't shed a tear
at her funeral.
Lots of folks did, but I didn't.
Growing up, the other kids
would play games
and joke with each other,
and they would cry...
if they got hurt
or if they were scared.
And I'd watch 'em.
I got pretty good at pretending.
Good enough, anyway.
Pretending I was like
the other kids.
Pretending I was...
normal.
That's when I realized
I had never known fear.
My whole life, I'd seen fear
in the eyes of
every man I ever met.
I've come to expect it.
Grown men, terrified when
they had no reason to be.
I remember this one man
who was looking for me
because I had shot
a couple of his friends.
He caught up with me
in a bathhouse.
My pistol's lying out of reach,
next to my clothes.
And I remember seeing
this man holding a gun
on a cold, naked man
sitting in a tub,
and yet, he was the one shaking.
Too scared to move.
So, I stood up from my bath,
and I quietly
walked over to the man
and I took his pistol away.
And then I shot him
dead with it.
He didn't even beg for his life.
And even though I could
recognize fear in men,
even to a point where I could
use it against them,
I can honestly say I had no
idea what it actually felt like.
It was as if...
I'd been born...
dead inside.
But I didn't care.
'Cause I was dead inside.
How did Mama change that?
When I met your mother,
there was no introduction.
There was no getting
to know each other.
And in that first moment,
I saw her.
I felt something.
Something I'd never felt before.
Love?
Fear.
Fear she wouldn't talk to me.
Fear she wouldn't love me.
Fear I couldn't
make her my wife.
Fear of losing her.
She was the only thing
I ever feared...
and the only thing I ever loved.
When they told me Mama was dead,
I didn't know how to feel.
She was your mother.
You feel sad. You feel loss.
Is that how you felt?
I felt pain.
Like a part of me
was killed with her.
Do you still feel like that?
When Mama died,
I didn't feel anything.
It was as if I died.
Like I was lost.
I was lying in my bed,
in my room...
in our house.
But it felt like I would
never find my way back
to those things again.
You will.
Do you know the man
who killed Mama?
The man the marshal
told us about?
James McCallister?
Tomorrow,
after the sun comes up...
can you teach me how to shoot?
Good.
I think I'd like that.
Oh! Son of a bitch.
Oh. Oh, damn it.
Now remember,
keep your left eye closed.
Let the barrel drift
right above your target.
When you're ready,
gently breathe
all the air out of your lungs
and let the barrel fall.
Time it so your breath ends
just as you line up your shot.
At the bottom of your breath,
squeeze the trigger, don't pull,
Squeeze with your whole hand.
Were you aiming for the hat?
Just below it.
I was aiming for his chest.
You pulled. You didn't squeeze.
Let's try it again.
What's wrong?
Can I try the pistol?
H'yah! Hit!
Remember to squeeze.
Don't pull.
Morning, Eustice.
Those turkey bungholes never
relieved me of duty last night.
Left me sittin' out there
all night!
Is that so?
Boys? Come on down.
What is it, boss?
Eustice here has a grievance
he would like to air with
the rest of the gang.
- Go ahead.
- You two!
You were supposed to relieve me
in my post after four hours.
And that didn't happen.
And that's bullshit!
Eustice, please accept
my sincerest apologies
on behalf of
the rest of the gang.
We sure are sorry,
ain't we, boys?
And why didn't you
just come get us?
What?
If we were supposed to
relieve you,
why didn't you just come get
one of us to take your place?
Eustice? Why didn't you just
come get one of the boys?
Well, I... I didn't want to
leave my post, you know?
Briggs is a dangerous man.
And if he would've seen
there was no guard,
he might have snuck
in here and got us.
You didn't...
fall asleep, did you?
No, boss.
Eustice...
you wouldn't be lying to me,
would you?
No, boss. I mean,
I... I might've...
I might've shut my eyes
for a second or two as I...
You know, was so tired.
It was... it was a
long ride and I... I...
Eustice, shh.
Oh.
Falling asleep on guard duty
is a terrible thing to do.
What if Briggs had shown up
and you'd been asleep?
Yeah. Yeah,
he might have snuck in and
got us, like you said.
No. I would have seen him.
Now, I did you a favor.
All right?
Next time you're on watch,
you get a little sleepy,
you just give that
broken finger a squeeze,
and you'll perk right back up.
What's wrong?
There's only one way into town.
If they're down there,
they'll be watching
everyone who comes in.
They left a message in the barn.
It felt familiar.
Like it was meant for me.
What'd it say?
I don't like walking in, not
knowing who I'm looking for.
If they know me,
it'll give them the edge.
They'll see me coming.
I won't see them.
Do you think they'll know me?
Now you ride into town casually.
You've been sent on an errand
from your parents' farm up the road.
Keep your head up,
and look at everyone carefully.
Head straight for
the mercantile.
Go inside and ask the man
to buy something.
And then casually ask if any
riders had come through town.
Whatever he tells you,
you bring that information
straight back to me.
Can I help you, young lady?
Young lady?
Pardon my manners.
You must have caught me daydreaming.
I almost forgot
why I came in here.
My mama got it in
her head yesterday
that she had to bake a cake
for the church potluck
this weekend.
Last year, she made a pie,
but the apples that she used
grew on Mr. Johnson's
apple tree,
the one back by his outhouse.
And wouldn't you know it,
those apples tasted
plum like shit
and made anyone who ate
them sick to their gut.
I tell ya', I think that
shit in that outhouse
soaked down into the roots
and changed the way
a basic apple can taste.
But Mr. Johnson says
that's a bunch of hooey,
and because of that,
he won't let Mama
have any more apples
for her apple pie,
which, as far as I'm concerned,
is fine by me and Mama
because like I mentioned before,
those apples
taste like shit anyhow.
Who the hell is Mr. Johnson?
Is this
the little girl you seen, Boots?
It is the little girl we
saw the other morning.
Hello there, little miss.
That's a fine horse
you're riding.
Couldn't help
but notice the saddle.
Wouldn't mind telling me
how you got it, would you?
Better yet...
Why don't you just tell me
where your daddy is?
Maria, this here is
my little sister.
Buenos dias.
Still no sign of him.
Hm.
He'll be around soon enough,
I 'spect.
This one hasn't
touched her food.
I 'spect she's
too scared to eat.
Is that it, little sister?
You too scared to eat?
No.
Of course not.
'Spect the daughter
of Colton Briggs
ain't scared of nothin'.
You boys hang that sign
outside like I asked?
Red paint. Just like you asked.
Good. Where's Big Mike?
He's got a good angle
at the road into town.
Ah, well.
One of you set up
at the other end of town.
- The other across the street.
- Yes, sir.
Oh, and, boys...
Stay out of sight, all right?
It's important he gets to
the middle of town
and sees our invitation
before we throw him his
little surprise party.
Boss, if we get a chance to put
a bullet in Colton Briggs,
we oughta do it.
It ain't smart playing games
with a fella like that.
Sounds like he's
the one who's scared.
Sure does, doesn't it?
You hear what little
sister just said?
You scared?
I'll take the other end of town.
Boss is
expecting Briggs anytime.
Might wanna wake your ass up.
- I'm awake.
- Good. Keep it that way.
We're supposed to let him get
into town before we kill him.
He wants him to see that we got
his daughter or something.
Makes sense.
You do yourself and
all of us a favor.
You see that son of a bitch,
you put a bullet in him.
H'yah!
Go back right there.
If you ain't too scared to eat,
why ain't you
touched your food yet?
It's probably poison.
So you is scared.
Scared of poison.
You don't have to be scared
to not eat poison.
Just not stupid.
You see this?
No poison.
I couldn't poison you
even if I wanted to.
Reckon it's some kind of
sin to poison your kin.
Stop saying that.
Stop sayin' what?
Stop calling me your sister.
We ain't kin.
You and I are most certainly kin
in almost all respects.
The uh... fruits of
your father's labors.
Sure as shootin'.
- You're a liar.
- I'm not saying that
your daddy knocked my mama up
and they made a baby.
No, no, no.
There was another man who had
the honors of my physical birth.
But he's not around no more...
on account of the day
I like to call my...
"spiritual birth."
You see, it was on that day
that your daddy...
he decided I didn't
need mine anymore.
He took him away from me.
Right there in front of me.
I watched him die.
Watched the life leave his eyes.
It was right then that
I stared into the eyes
of the man who killed him.
And you know what
your daddy did?
He stared right back at me.
Then he...
he got on his horse
and he rode away.
But not all of him.
No. See, he...
he left a tiny little
piece of himself
buried deep inside of me.
Like a seed.
Workin' on
a little insurance policy.
We don't need those
boys gettin' any ideas
about running off
with the money.
It used to be
you couldn't find nothing
around these parts
except tequila.
Finding whiskey in Santa Rosa?
It's progress.
You see, the problem
with progress
is that something's gonna go.
In with the new,
out with the old.
That's the way of the world.
But this transition...
Oh, it's rarely a peaceful one.
No, ma'am.
Transition of power
is one of violence.
Necessary violence.
Which is why we're here today.
You see...
I got a monster inside of me.
The devil himself.
That devil can't get out
as long as there's another
devil out there in the world.
Both these devils...
can't exist at the same time.
Oh, I get it.
You're crazy.
But don't worry, my father will
be here soon. He'll fix that.
Hmm, you know,
I'm glad we had
this time together.
Get to know each other
as siblings.
'Cause after tonight,
after your father gets here...
well, I'm gonna be
your new daddy.
And we'll see what needs fixin'.
Eustice!
Oh, he's here.
He's here!
Help!
He's here.
Don't, mister, please, don't kill...
Holy shit.
He's here!
He done killed Big Mike,
and got one of them
Mexican cowboys!
The devil does not disappoint.
Let's go see Pa.
Walk.
He went down that alley,
behind these buildings.
Go around and flush him out.
Christ Almighty.
Eustice, did you hear what said?
Go!
I got you, pendejo.
You see him?
He must've circled back.
I got him! He got Boots,
but I shot him!
- Is he dead?
- No. I only winged him.
But he's got a bullet in him,
sure as shit.
He's holed up in that building
over there by the alley.
You're sure about that?
He seem like the type of
fella to just hole up
and wait for us to come get him?
Guess we'll see.
You two.
You see that mercantile?
Now, the villain that killed
your buddy is inside.
Why don't you go
in there and get him?
I'll double your pay
if you bring him out alive.
Be careful now. He's a snake.
He may be a snake but he ain't
- a Goddamn wizard.
- Eustice...
I need you to just trust me.
Can you do that?
Shame to have to let you
go so close to the end.
Briggs!
I'm calling you out.
Ain't that what
you boys used to do?
Call each other out?
Settle your differences
in the street?
Let's do this the old way!
Holster that pistol, Mister.
I swear to God,
I'll kill this little girl.
Hello, handsome.
Remember me?
No.
Get your hands up.
Both of 'em.
It's busted.
You got him, boss.
What are we gonna do?
You really don't remember me.
I gotta say, hurts my feelings.
But I guess it's
not too surprising.
I was just a little whooper
last time you saw me.
The important thing is...
I remember you.
Don't worry.
I'm okay.
I definitely remember you,
Colton Briggs.
Every time I close my eyes,
I see your face...
staring me down.
I smell the smoke
from your guns,
hear the noises my
daddy made as he died.
And that's why we're here.
You, me...
your little girl.
She never would
tell me her name,
but it don't matter none.
We're just one big happy family.
You see...
we're gonna have a showdown,
you and me.
And you get the opportunity
to put a bullet in my head
just like you did my daddy.
And if you do that,
Eustice here,
he's gonna blow
your little girl's head off.
- Boss, just kill him!
- Shut up!
Now...
you kill me...
and watch your little girl die.
Or save your daughter,
and watch me take your place.
Brooke.
I have all I need.
See that I'm tended to.
No.
And... I love you.
No!
Holy shit.
I did it!
I killed him!
I'm so sorry, Daddy.
I love you so much.
I did it!
I'm so sorry.
I killed Colton Briggs!
I killed him!
You hear that, Daddy?
I killed him.
It's...
It's you.
You're the monster...
You're no kin.
Brooke...
take your mother.
She'll tell you what to do.
You alive?
Found another body
in the back alley back there.
That makes four of 'em.
More or less what I expected.
Round up the bodies
and let's get 'em back.
Will they bring him home?
Yeah, I suppose they will.
Thank you.
Marshal?
What are you going to tell them?
I thought I might bring you in
for what you and your daddy did.
Tell them how you captured us
and tortured us and...
left us to die
out in the desert.
But I suppose the judge would
just say that you were...
following your
daddy's orders and...
blind with rage over
your mama's murder...
even though you and I both
know that ain't quite true.
And in that case,
your daddy would be
buried as a criminal.
And you would go home
to try to figure out what to
do with your daddy's store.
Found a strongbox
in the saloon, Marshal.
Good work, Corporal.
That'll be all.
And then I considered telling
them that you and your daddy...
came along, and you
saved my deputy's life...
by performing field surgery
on his shoulder.
Then you proceeded to track
down your mother's murderers
and then he was killed in the
process of their apprehension
in which case you
would still go home.
So, I figure since the outcomes
in both those scenarios
are the same,
I prefer the story
that doesn't involve
me getting captured by
a 12-year-old girl.
And maybe in that version,
we can forget all about
that strong box, too.
In that version...
my daddy gets to be a hero?
In exchange for your discretion.
Yes.
I believe that
sounds about right.
Well then, it's decided.
Marshal?
Did you find your horse?
Tied up at the edge of town.
Just like he said.
You get on home, little Briggs.
Take care of your daddy's store.
H'yah.
You hear that, Daddy?
You're gonna be a hero.
Mama would be so proud.
Maria, isn't it?
Si, Senorita.
Why don't you fetch me
my brother's saddlebag
from inside the saloon?
I best be getting on home.